Hi. Thank you all for attending our talk
today.
As unsupervised as we are.
I'm Emily Johnson.
I'm an associate professor
of English and core faculty in the text
and technology PhD program
at the University of Central Florida.
And I was supposed to let Vee go first
to introduce themselves.
Go ahead Vee.
Hi everybody.
I am Vee Kennedy and I'm an instructor
of writing and rhetoric
at the University of Central Florida,
where I am also a candidate in the Text
and Technology PhD program.
If it sounds like I just had to read
that off to remind myself I did.
E I read mind too. It's okay.
We are two unsupervised
stress speakers here to present to you
Luffy Pumpkin cheesecake a critical baking
exploration of unsupervised processes.
We created an interactive simulation
that you see before
you collaboratively with each other
and with cloud.
AI cloud suggested that we describe
our creation process as negotiating
this simulation into existence,
which feels very accurate.
The simulation is obviously a play
on the conference theme, unsupervised,
and we set out to create it
in a very unsupervised manner,
like as in the machine
learning definition of unsupervised,
where there is no human guidance
or label data sets.
I initially thought
Claude would just be able to take
my fantastic ideas from my mind
and digitally produce
whatever I had in my head,
and I was absolutely not how it went.
And to be fair, this was before the paid
version, before coworker, and paid before
I had the paid version and had coworker
and fable and all the improvements.
Cloud really struggled.
It couldn't find the Kellogg's recipe
that this is based on, so it guessed
the recipe is wrong.
So if you want the real recipe,
please feel free to message me.
At one point,
the mixer vanished after weeks of trying
to get it to display my beautiful mint
green KitchenAid.
My actual prompt was okay, no revert.
The reflections wouldn't save
even when Claude said they were saved.
Negotiation really is a polite description
of my side of the chat
with Claude for a lot of this,
but you'll notice additional plays
on supervision throughout.
We begin here in the kitchen,
where we find ourselves unsupervised.
Again, we're stress bakers,
and once I add the cream cheese here
and complete the step,
you can see that we are
at the unsupervised hour of 2:38 a.m..
I believe it was 2:38 a.m.
when I was writing my draft of this
abstract for submission,
and that's why it's 2:38 a.m.
in this simulation.
So every step ends with beautiful
field notes.
These are ours, not the machines.
It tried to eat hours several times.
So these went through a lot of iterations
even without Claude.
Now mine here starts by saying
I forgot to let the cream cheese soften
at room temperature.
For a while before starting,
I was doing email.
When your hands are in dough or batter,
they can't be an email.
That's a real truth friends.
Well, this is what I tell myself,
but at this time it was 2:38 a.m.
and I was simultaneously
in email and batter, which is, you know,
something has gone terribly wrong.
Now, as I gazed into the mixing bowl,
the cream cheese and sugar begin to blend
and the mixture warms and softens.
No one will ever know that I forgot
to get that cream cheese out early.
Now we are calling the stress baking.
This is not a new term.
A few scholars have taken it
seriously as a coping practice, mostly
in the pandemic. Literature.
Alan grad student
out there who was looking at baking
as coping and connection and Covid.
And then we had some folks out there
also say, like literally prescribing
each other sourdough
as a remedy for stress in the lockdown,
because the process of making sourdough
is this extraordinarily slow process
that forces you to do
all of these menial steps over and over.
But alas, the lockdown is over,
and here I am, and it's 2:38 a.m.
and I am still baking
because the conditions
that created this kind of stress baking
did not really start
or end with the lockdown,
just became something that we focused on
a little bit more in the lockdown
and then proceeded to kind of move away
from after the lockdown,
at least move away from acknowledging.
So we'll go ahead and move on
here to the next step.
All right.
So we're going to do sugar and pumpkin
pie spice.
Enjoy the emojis.
The happy warm smell of the pumpkin pie
spice
takes me briefly to the holiday break.
Then another buzz from my watch
jerks me back to reality.
And that proposal let's do tomorrow.
So the frame for this project,
of course, is critical.
Making that Natalie Loveless etc.
started as a silly experiment, honestly,
which is like,
let's
see if we can do a critical baking thing.
It'll be fun.
But honestly, the more we think about it,
the more it is to think about right?
The simulation here is a flattening.
Nick Susanna's flattens
the baking process right, removing
not only the three dimensional material
tactile elements of baking,
but this sounds, the smells
and the tastes that happen when you bake.
We took baking the one activity
that pulls us away from the screen
and put it back inside one so that we
could think out loud about why we do it.
Okay, and I have to do the eggs.
And then B has.
There we go I missed one okay.
Don't worry.
There's no way to mess this up.
In fact, I'm not even sure how many eggs
we just put in.
Was it too?
Was it three?
I don't know, I stare into the middle
distance, the void.
There's a joke
about Nietzsche here somewhere.
But this cake, it must resist philology.
At least more than I need to resist
my email at 2 a.m..
Well, it's fluffy looking anyway, right?
At least some things it's thought to be.
So this is where baking is starting to do
what a meditation app does not.
It occupies your hands
and your short term memory at once.
You cannot draft or revise and resubmit
while counting eggs.
Well, you can try,
but then you might end up protein
maxing in your cheesecake
because there's a lot of extra eggs
in there.
Researchers on the therapeutic side, like
so's, work on baking as confectionery.
Art therapy describe this as the value
of the tactile sequence sensory work.
We put it more plainly the recipe
is the only deadline in the room,
and it's a deadline
that ends and it ends in cheesecake.
Mid brainstorm,
Claude asks us whether or not stress
baking helped us
think or stop thinking. We?
You still really don't agree on that.
So moving forward.
Unsupervised.
Claude also decided
that the pumpkin ingredient here
should be represented
as a jack o'lantern emoji.
A grinning Halloween decoration
headed for cheesecake.
Somehow I told it to go ahead
and use Libby's the iconic pumpkin cam.
I usually use the off brand
if we're being honest, but we tried to.
We tried some realism elsewhere
to like Philadelphia Cream Cheese and the
McCormick Spice jar, but they came out
so badly that we reverted back to the.
For those.
So the Libby's can sort of remains
the lone icon of supervision here.
So I'll complete this step
and we'll get some
pumpkin looking batter in a second focus.
I say aloud to myself,
where was I in the recipe?
I did the eggs right.
What about the sugar?
Isn't there supposed to be vanilla
in this thing too?
Part of why I do this is to force myself
to focus on something that isn't work,
and I literally have to tell myself
to focus while I'm making.
Oh, and then go ahead and be.
Right.
Now here my field notes say I definitely
did not match these graham crackers
finally enough when I was making the crust
during my zoom office hours earlier.
But alas, what's done is done.
The thrashing they received from the
not rolling pin that I fashioned
out of a can of Campbell's
soup was, well, efficient and ingenious,
which are words that were used
in my most recent annual evaluation.
Yes.
Notice what has leaked into the kitchen,
the language of my most recent
annual avow, that is the supervised
half of our title annual evasion
alley, annual evaluations, student credit
hours, that prospectus.
I'm totally been writing.
You know, the audit follows
you home and narrates you.
It joins your graham crackers, taking
hours away from academic production.
To make something that we give away
is small.
A small, deliberate act of resistance,
something tasty and fun.
As if to say, I'm struggling,
you're struggling.
This fluffy pumpkin cheesecake can nourish
our physical bodies and our body minds.
In this meeting.
That should have been an email.
We wanted the simulation to look more
splattered with cheesecake as we go.
So, as you might notice in the background
behind the field notes,
there are these little blob like things.
They're supposed to be batter.
It's supposed to be Claude's
best approximation of a mess,
but it really is just a reminder
that Claude can't make a real mess, right?
We were hoping for something
that would look more like a crime scene.
Is anyone who has ever set foot in
my kitchen can tell you post, bake.
If you go into my kitchen,
it looks like something died there.
And it wasn't just vanilla, right?
On a more literal note, Claude
quite literally can't make images.
It can use SVG files
to kind of put together pictures of shapes
that are blob together,
so we can get a sense of what process
occurred here, that Claude didn't
literally have a picture of a stand mixer,
but it's probably seen
some pictures of a stand mixer,
and therefore it kind of tried to cobble
one together out of shapes.
So in some ways,
this is now me looking back into Claude
and imagining what its process was.
So I am now
supervising my supervisor here.
We see you, Claude.
We know what you can and cannot do.
You were never able to actually pull
together a beautiful mint green KitchenAid
stand mixer, but you could make
some shapes that kind of made one.
All right. But who am I to judge here?
This cheesecake
would be a lot less fluffy and delicious
if it were only mixed by human hands.
Continue.
All right,
so here we're putting it in the oven.
My internal dialog runs unchecked.
Check the oven.
Make sure nothing is in there.
Check again to make sure the wire rack
is set at the right height.
30 minutes. Don't
forget to start the timer. 30 minutes.
Don't forget to start the timer
30 minutes. Set.
Okay, now you can check your email,
but don't go too far from the kitchen.
Again, my actual insight here to my brain
as we bake
academia
feels really supervised at the moment.
It has us constantly jumping
from task to tasks, from topic to topic,
and the feeling that
because of that supervision,
we constantly need to be available
and productive
is something that both of us
clearly feel very strongly at the moment.
And it's come through in our simulation
here.
And again,
we're trying to resist that all in
at least this very small way of baking.
Okay.
All right.
Continuing forth, we
put the cake out on the rack to cool off.
We hope. Right.
We hope we remember to do this.
There's a chance of still in the oven.
So it says in an hour
when the cheesecake cools
I can get into the fridge and nap with it
for just enough time.
Shower and get to campus.
What is sleep like?
Actual sleep?
And then Microsoft Office dings again
and lets me know
that I have another email or something
else.
Some other deadline I forgot about.
Maybe if I write really fast
I can get a little bit of a nap in.
Well again, here we are in our process,
being reminded of all of this supervision
and yet non supervision.
As an aside, my KitchenAid stand mixer
at home is not beautiful.
Mint green it's teal.
I bought it for myself
with some of my student loan refund money
one term at the beginning of my PhD,
which means I've almost assuredly
not actually paid for it
and probably will be paying for it
until I die.
But should public service
loan forgiveness
go the way of the dodo
as it appears to be,
this KitchenAid will continue to sustain
me and us collectively as a community.
We want to be careful
not to sell you self-care,
and Warren warn us that self-care
and institutional hands becomes
one more individual duty,
one more thing to fail
at while the conditions
producing the stress go and examined.
What redeems this cheesecake, however,
is the fact that it does not stay home.
It goes to campus,
to colleagues, to community,
and it facilitates those one minute
long conversations where we catch up
with each other about not work,
and we say things like, how are you?
And get responses
like, oh, we don't ask that anymore,
shared distant cheesecake.
Continue.
And I feel
like this started as sort of like a mini
therapy session in our reflections,
but it's turned into a real love
letter for our communities
for which we make.
So I'll go ahead and complete this step
after refrigerate.
Will I remember to bring this
to campus tomorrow or will I forget again?
The recipe is done, but the anxiety isn't.
It never is.
But at least now there's cheesecake too.
And so that's the end of our simulation
here I want to point out it is public.
You can go to the link
I think it's posted somewhere.
I'll post it again if you want
you can go here and edit reflections.
And so this is sort of our invitation.
Feel free to go in
and replace our field notes with your own.
It should save now pending.
I haven't actually tested it,
but cloud saw as it saves.
But at the top you notice
it says changes are saved to your account.
There there's no account.
We left a few unsupervised
things for your enjoyment.
All right.
So that's that's fine.
And we're good.
Yeah.
Baking will not fix academia
and neither will this simulation.
But at least we can pretend
we have cheesecake.
Thank you.